masterpass.com 2015-02-12

# Privacy Notice

**Effective Date:** **September 20, 2013** ****

**MasterCard: _MasterPass ™_ Wallet/ _MasterPass_ Online™ Privacy Policy**

MasterCard International Incorporated and its affiliates (“ **MasterCard** ”) respect your privacy.  This Privacy Policy applies to _MasterPass_ Wallet and/or _MasterPass_ Online (the “Site”) (collectively, “ ** _MasterPass_ Wallet Services**”).  It describes the types of personal data we collect in connection with the _MasterPass_ Wallet Services, the purposes for which we collect that personal data, the other parties with whom we may share it and the measures we take to protect the security of the data. It also tells you about your rights and choices with respect to your personal data, and how you can reach us to update your contact information or get answers to questions you may have about our privacy practices.  The entities responsible for the collection and use of your personal data in the context of the _MasterPass_ Wallet Services are: 

MasterCard Europe Sprl                                MasterCard International Inc                     

Chaussée de Tervuren 198A       Attn: Global Privacy & Data Usage Officer

B-1410, Waterloo                             2000 Purchase Avenue

Belgium                                                Purchase NY 10577

                                                                U.S.A.

Please note that for those consumers who reside in France, MasterCard France (and not MasterCard Europe Sprl) will be the appropriate entity responsible for the collection and use of your personal data in the context of the _MasterPass_ Wallet Services. Reference may be made to MasterCard International Inc. as the parent company of MasterCard France.

MasterCard France

112 Avenue Kléber 

75784 Paris Cedex 15

France

Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:

**1.   Personal Data We Collect** ** __**

**2.   How We Use the Personal Data We Collect** ** __**

**3\. Personal Data We Share** ** __**

**4\. Your Rights and Choices** ** __**

**5\. How We Protect Your Personal Data** ** __**

**6\. Data Transfers** ** __**

**7.   Feature and Links to Other Websites** ** __**

**8\. Update to this Privacy Policy** ** __**

**9\. How to Contact Us** ** __**

**a.        ****Personal Data Provided by You**

In connection with your use of _MasterPass_ Wallet Services, we ask you for certain personal data upon registration, on applications forms or other forms,  such as your name, home address, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, email address, national identity card number in some instances, user name, password, answers to our security questions, loyalty card information and payment card information. The provision of your personal data for the purposes listed below is voluntary.  However, in some circumstances, withholding your personal data will mean that you cannot take advantage of certain products or services.

**b.       ****Personal Data Provided by Participating Merchants in Connection with Your Use of the _MasterPass_ Wallet**

We receive certain data from merchants about your transactions using the _MasterPass_ Wallet, including but not limited to, stock-keeping unit data, description of items, quantity, price and subtotal and payment cards registered with the _MasterPass_ Wallet, merchant name, currency, amount, date and time of order and information about whether or not the order was completed. 

**c.        ****Personal Data We Collect Automatically**

We also may collect certain information by automated means (such as cookies and web beacons) when you visit our website. 

_Cookies._ Like many companies, we may use “cookies” on our websites.  Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer’s hard drive or your mobile device’s memory when you visit certain websites. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular website and facilitating your navigation through a site. We may use cookies to tell us, for example, how many users visited our websites and the pages accessed, user’s shopping behavior and preferences, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor, to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest, to tell your preferences and personal settings and previous activities performed by you. This information allows us to make improvements and updates to our website, and to determine the effectiveness of our promotions and campaigns. Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies.  Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of all our website features.

_Web Beacons._ Certain pages on our website may contain “web beacons” (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). Web beacons do not typically collect any other information than what your browser provides us with as a standard part of any internet communication. These web beacons allow us to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page and the information in cookies. We may use web beacons to enhance your online experience, in the same way as we may use cookies (described above).We do not use them to identify individual users personally. If you turn off cookies, the web beacon will no longer be able to track your specific activity. The web beacon may, however, continue to collect information about visits from your IP-address.

If you are accessing the _MasterPass_ Wallet Services from Europe, please refer to our [Cookie Notice](https://masterpass.com/Wallet/CookieNotice) for further information. 

We may use the personal data we obtain about you to:

  * Create and manage your online account, provide our products and services, and respond to your inquiries;
  * Validate your payment card information; 
  * Provide, administer and communicate with you about products, services and promotions (including contests, sweepstakes, programs and other offers), including the display of customized content and advertising; 
  * Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims and other liabilities, and manage risk exposure and franchise quality;
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including by developing new products and services; managing our communications; determining the effectiveness of our advertising; analyzing our products, services and websites; facilitating the functionality of our websites; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities);
  * Assist third parties in the provision of products or services that you request from third parties;
  * Monitor the use of and improve our interactive assets;
  * Perform data analyses (including anonymization of personal information) to determine, among other measurements, business performance, number of registrants, channels, transaction spend and site performance;
  * Enforce our [_MasterPass_ Wallet Consumer Terms of Use](https://masterpass.com/Wallet/TermsAndConditions);
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements and industry standards and our policies; and
  * Perform auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services.

We also may use the information in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection.

We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal data we collect about you, except as described in this Privacy Policy or otherwise disclosed to you at the time the data is collected.

We may share the personal data we collect with our affiliates, wallet providers, financial institutions that issue payment cards or process payment card transactions and merchants.We share personal data to perform and/or facilitate payment card transactions (including card fraud detection and prevention) and to provide the _MasterPass_ Wallet Services that you request. For example, in the course of supplying the _MasterPass_ Wallet Services, we may provide an individual's card data to a financial institution about their cardholders' transactions which MasterCard processes. In the course of supplying some of our products we may also provide personal data to a merchant to facilitate a payment card transaction.

We also may share aggregated or anonymized data with participating merchants, wallet providers and financial institutions. 

We also may share personal data with our service providers who perform services on our behalf. We do not authorize these service providers to use or disclose the data except as necessary to perform certain services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. We require these service providers by contract to appropriately safeguard the privacy and security of personal data they process on our behalf.

We also may disclose data about you: (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (ii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual fraudulent or illegal activity.

We also reserve the right to transfer personal data we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will inform you in due course about the identity of the new data controller, as well as of the details about how you may exercise your rights of access, correction and suppression after the sale or transfer has taken place, and we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

You may have certain rights under applicable law regarding the personal data  we maintain about you. We offer you certain choices about what personal data we collect from you, how we use that information, and how we communicate with you.

At any time, you can access your account by logging into your account. You can view or change your personal details and manage your marketing preferences here. You can at any time tell us not to send you marketing communications by e-mail by clicking on the unsubscribe link within the marketing e-mails you receive from us or by changing your settings on your preferences page on your account. You also may opt-out of receiving marketing e-mails by [clicking here](http://www.mastercard.us/privacy/email-opt-out.html). We will apply your preferences going forward. In some circumstances, withdrawing your consent to our use or disclosure of your personal data will mean that you cannot take advantage of certain  products or services.

As indicated above, we may anonymize personal data to perform data analyses. If you would like to opt-out from data analytics, [click here](https://www.mastercard.com/us/personal/en/general/data-analytics-opt-out.html). 

You may withdraw your consent to certain uses of personal data we collect about you by automated means when you visit our website.  Specifically, we may use cookies to collect information about your website visits.  To withdraw your consent to the aggregation and analysis of your data collected on our websites, please [click here](https://www.mastercard.com/us/personal/en/general/web-analytics-opt-out.html). 

You may be able to link your device to the _MasterPass_ Wallet by using Intel Identity Protection® Technology (“IPT”). Additional disclosures about data processing through IPT will be provided upon enrollment.

Where required by law, MasterCard obtains your prior opt-in consent at the time of collection for the processing of (i) personal data for marketing purposes,(ii) personal data deemed sensitive pursuant to applicable law , or (iii) personal data to be used for other data processing activities for which your consent may be required.

Subject to applicable law, you may have the right to request access to and receive information about the personal data we maintain about you, update and correct inaccuracies in your personal data, to object to the processing of your personal data and have the information blocked or deleted, as appropriate. The right to access personal information may be limited in some circumstances by local law requirements. To update your preferences, ask us to remove your information from our mailing lists or submit an access request, please contact us as specified in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, unauthorized alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, misuse, and any other unlawful form of processing of the personal data in our possession.  The types of measures we take vary with the type of data, and how it is collected and stored.

When you provide personal data online, we use the industry standard for encryption on the Internet  – Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology – to help protect the data that you provide.  This Internet encryption standard scrambles data as it travels from your device to our server.  You will know that you are in a secure area of the Site when a lock icon appears on your screen that the “http” prefix of our URL address changes to “https. ”  The “s” represents “secure”.  We also use digital certificates to ensure that you are connected to the authentic Site.

We will never ask you for your password in any unsolicited communication (including unsolicited correspondence, such as letters, phone calls or e-mail messages).  If you believe your user name and password have been compromised, please contact us by following the instructions provided in the section "How to Contact Us" below. 

We also take measures to destroy or permanently de-identify personal data when there is no longer a business need to keep the information and in any case, for no longer than 13 months from the last time you have logged on to your account.

We may transfer personal data to countries other than the country in which the data was originally collected for the purposes specifed in “How We Use Personal Data We Collect” section above. These countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your personal data to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Policy.

We comply with applicable legal requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of personal data  to countries outside of the European Economic Area or Switzerland. 

In particular, we will transfer your personal data to the United States. MasterCard is certified under the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor privacy framework as agreed by the U.S. Department of Commerce, European Commission and Switzerland regarding the collection, storage, use, transfer and other processing of personal data transferred from the European Economic Area or Switzerland to the U.S.  U.S. organisations complying with this framework are considered to provide an adequate level of data protection. [Click here](http://www.mastercard.us/privacy/safe-harbor.html) to view MasterCard’s Safe Harbor Privacy Policy or visit [www.mastercard.com](http://www.mastercard.com/).

On our Site you may choose to use certain features for which we partner with other entities or click on links to other websites for your convenience and information.  These features, which may include social networking and geographic location tools, and other websites may operate independently from MasterCard.  They may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review.  To the extent any features or linked websites you visit are not owned or operated by MasterCard, we are not responsible for the sites’ content, any use of the sites, or the privacy practices of the sites.

This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal data practices.  We will post a prominent notice on our websites to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Policy and indicate at the top of the notice when it was most recently updated.

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or if you would like to exercise your rights or to update the information we have about you or your preferences, please [click here](https://www.mastercard.com/us/personal/en/general/contact-us.html). You may also contact us by writing to: 

Global Privacy & Data Usage Officer  
MasterCard Worldwide  
2000 Purchase Street  
Purchase, New York 10577  
USA

Or: 

Global Privacy & Data Usage Officer  
MasterCard Europe sprl  
Chaussee de Tervuren 198A  
B-1410, Waterloo  
Belgium

Or 

For those consumers who reside in France, please contact:

MasterCard France

112 Avenue Kléber 

75784 Paris Cedex 15

France
